Yufei Liu

Location: Hamilton New Zealand | Bachelor

E-mail: flying3615@163.com

My Github repository

Blog

Self-assessment

I have more than 5 Years of experience in Java SE/Java EE development and design, including 3 years of huge-scale JAVA program development experience with solid knowledge of JAVA enterprise and JAVA core programming, including but not limit to Web server development expertise. I've served as a senior Java developer on a major project for Alcatel-Lucent Telecom Company(merged by Nokia now) with the main responsibilities of designing and architect new features requested by customer for the product which is a core network management system. Currently, I'm severing to a relatively small but pretty dynamic and vibrant company which going to IPO. My responsibilities include witting technical architecture document and monitoring projects schedules, as well as providing development guideline, etc. Besides Java, I am also a omnivorous developer and am familiar with Groovy, Python and Linux shell script language, as well as using front-side framework like Angular.JS, Javascript, and JQuery. I'm also a big fan of Scala and Kotlin, moderner languages than Java, supporting pure functional programming and making concurrent programming much easier. I've used Scala and its serial tech stack libraries to develop a small full <u>inverted index searcher</u> for my GD homework

Work Experience

2016/11 - 2017/02

<u>Shandong Shenhao Property Management Co., Ltd.</u>|Senior Software Engineer IT Service/General IT

Job Description:

Dating Website Project Senior Java Developer

Joined the team as a senior Java programmer, which job mainly was focusing on website Optimization and Architecture refinement. With using react architecture, the throughtput of website enhanced for 4 times. The refinement also includes Performance testing(Gatling), code

Analysis(SonarQube) and Jira-Jenkins Integration. I've setup those DevOps tools by myself for the company.

Technologies Utilized:

Java8, SpringMVC, Hibernate, Redis, MongoDB.

2016/07 - 2016/08

F6 Digital Media & Marketing | Internship

IT Service/General IT

Job Description:

Internship

WordPress Web Developer

Worked alongside with other developers to development & deliver high quality clients' websites. Daily websites maintenance(Data Backup/Restore) Websites migration

Technologies Utilized:

WordPress, Docker, MySQL.

2010/11 - 2016/05

Qingdao Centling Information Technology Co., Ltd. | Tech Lead Telecom Operators/Service Providers

Job Description:

Qingdao Centling Information Technology Co., Ltd Tech Lead

Making technic framework decision and base platform development. Training new staff for quickly picking up new technic tools and modern frameworks Leading team to finish several project including e-commerce, information manage system.

Technologies Utilized:

Jhipster, Angular JS1, Groovy on Grails, Docker, PHP

2010/11 - 2015/05

<u>Qingdao Alcatel-Lucent R&D</u>|Senior Software Engineer Telecom Operators/Service Providers

Job Description:

Alcatel-Lucent COM(Centre Operation Manager) - Fault Management

Senior Software Engineer This is an on-going project for Alcatel-Lucent I 've been working for 3 years, a large-scale network management system which involves almost one hundred developers

aiming for proving customers with high expandability and flexibility to manage a large network environment.,

Designers and engineers are throughout the world (mainly in US, France & China) to maintain and develop it. The core technique includes Java EE, Linux K Shell script and Oracle Database. This product is primarily divided into 4 parts: Fault Management, Performance Management, Network Element Provisioning and Security authentication system. I am primarily responsible for development of the Fault System.

Technologies Utilized:

JavaEE(JMS,EJB,JMX,etc), JBoss, Linux Shell, Oracle, Corba Notification Service

2009/08 - 2010/11

<u>Beijing Zhaopin.com</u>|Software Developer IT Service/General IT

Job Description:

ZhaoPin Corporation Java Developer

Customer Relationship Management (CRM) an internal enterprise system Web developer

This system is designed for collecting statistics of sales' daily phone volume, and the result data will evaluate sales' performance. I was responsible for the module which technologies are mainly applied DWR+SPRNG framework. Database layer used Spring's JdbcTemplate to access data. It's a typical DB drive system with a Web UI exposing to company stuff to deal daily works, and provide daily report to the management department to evaluate individual's performance.

My role and responsibilities were as follows: Develop and achieve data flow invocation from Web interface to Server Side communication Develop web page with JavaScript

Technologies Utilized:

Java, jQuery, DWR, Spring

Project Experience

• 2015/05 -- 2016/05

Several E-commercial projects software environment: LAMP

hardware environment: AWS, ECS+RDS

development tools: IntelliJ Idea

Responsibilities:

Leading a team to finish customer required web site building. Main job was to develop back-end PHP development and some front-end JS&CSS optimize.

Project Description:

The projects are relatively similar based on our company e-commercial infrastructure with a

whole process of place-order, customer-management, goods-management,etc.

For external interfaces, we integrated the projects with all pay, we chat pay and some other 3rd party data provider like logistic information interface, customer service interface and ERP systems.

• 2014/03 -- 2014/06

China Institute of Microwave - File Management System

software environment: Spring, SpringMVC, Hibernate Oracle 11g CentOS

hardware environment: x86 development tools: Eclipse

Responsibilities:

Server side architecture and designs of all testing cases

Communicate with stakeholders and design the interface

Coordinate with other developers to implement this system

Create framework infrastructure and Java coding in accordance with JavaEE Standards

Project Description:

As Working with a team of 10 developers on designing a remote files manage system part of a development team of 10 engineers, According to the requirement of the institute, we designed a file management system including file processing, uploading and downloading in a distribution environment. This project's techniques include Spring full stack framework and Hibernate ORM and Java multi-thread programming. For the client side, we used C# to compile.

• 2011/10 -- 2015/05

Alcatel-Lucent COM(Centre Operatoin Manager) – Fault Management software environment: Java 1.7, RedHat 6.5 Jboss4.2.3GA, Oracle 11g, Corba Notification Service JMS,EJB

hardware environment: HP Gen8/Gen6

development tools: Eclipse,

Responsibilities:

The key person responsible for the development of Fault Management module

Design and develop new features as well as fix bugs and technical support, based on client's feedback

Team representative to communicate with outside development teams to validate feasibility of creative implementation

Redesign and adapt the legacy interfaces to interact with a new Web UI by using AngularJS and intermediate layer using Django

Project Description:

This is an on-going project for Alcatel-Lucent I 've been working for 3 years, a large-scale network management system which involves almost one hundred developers aiming for proving customers with high expansibility and flexibility to manage a large network environment., Ddesigners and engineers are throughout the world (mainly in US, France & China) to maintain and develop it. The core technique includes Java EE, Linux K Shell script and Oracle Database. This product is primarily divided into 4 parts: Fault Management, Performance Management, Network Element Provisioning and Security authentication system. I am primarily responsible for development of the Fault System.

• 2010/12 -- 2011/12

Alcatel Shanghai Bell WAM& Alcatel Lucent WLAN management

software environment: Java Flex Mysql

hardware environment: x86

development tools: Eclipse, Flex Builder Spring Mybatis Shell

Responsibilities:

As a member of 5 persons agile team, to develop Alcatel Shanghai Bell WAM & Alcatel Lucent WLAN management, which using the same architecture, including Spring 2.5 Mybatis 3.0 Mysql6.0.

I was responsible for back-end designing and DB table defining.

Project Description:

These two projects are all B/S and used to manage the access network management. Server side use adventNet to communicate the network elements, business logical processing.

Front side used Flex as the presentation layer, achieved via Twaver framework which is a famous network topology framework.

Education Background

• 2005/09 -- 2009/09

Qingdao University of Science and Technology | Information Engineering | Bachelor

Training

• 2009/02 -- 2009/03

Thoughtworks

Training Course:

OOA/D design patterns

Training Location: BeiJing

Description in Details:

General training about multiple design patterns in Java development.

• 2008/12 -- 2009/06

Tarena IT Education Compay

Training Course:

Senior Java Development Courses Tarena IT Education Company

Training Location: Beijing

Description in Details: Courses include Linux, SQL, JavaScript and Java development.

Two commercial level projects had been done when during the training courses, which are Telecom billing system&online shopping web site.

Language Skills

English:proficient

Mandarin:native

Programming Skills

Backend

JavaEE, JMS, SpringMVC, SpringBoot, Hibernate, ElasticSearch, Redis Akka,RxJava,Functional Programming

Frontend

AngularJS, React, JQuery, Gulp/Bower, NPM

DevOps

GitHub, JIRA, Jenkins, Docker, Maven/Gradle/SBT, IntelliJ IDEA

Testing

Junit, Spock, ScalaTest

Professional Skills(months)

Java, Kotlin, Groovy, Scala, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Linux Script,